早安   嗨
Morning. Hi.
昨晚约会还顺利吗
Hi! Oh, How was your date last night?
很不错  太好了
Pretty good. Oh, good.
天啊  我真的很抱歉
Aah! My God. Sorry about that.
没事  真的是太棒了
Okay, really good.
我得走了  我要迟到了
Anyway I gotta go. I'm late for work.
什么啊  你要把她丢给我
What-what?! You're going to leave this person with me?
别担心  她真的很棒
Hey, Don't worry, she's a terrific girl.
你能帮我一个忙吗
And hey listen, could you do me a favor?
她出来了  你能跟她说我不想定下来吗   谢谢你啊
When she comes out could you just mention that I'm not looking for a serious relationship? That'd be great.
什么  你在开玩笑吗
Why?! What, are you kidding?
不经意跟她提起这件事  装做轻描淡写的样子
Just casually slip it in, you know. Lay the groundwork.
告诉她我是个独行侠  不  我是爱的逃犯
Tell her uh, I'm a loner. No, an outlaw.
她不会想跟我这种人混在一起
she doesn't want to get mixed up with the likes of me.
太复杂了
Y'know what? That's a lot to remember.
我不能直接告诉她你是猪吗
Can't I tell her that you're a pig?
我会找时间亲自打电话给她
Hey, I'm gonna call her later myself.
我保证
Honest.
钱德以前常这么做  他还会做煎饼给她吃
Oh come on, Chandler used to do it. He'd even make the girl pancakes!
他还会多做几块留给我吃
Plus, He'd make extras and leave them for me.
算了吧   我什么都不会告诉她   这不是我的责任
Well forget it, I'm not telling that girl anything. It's not my responsibility.
好吧
Fine.
那些煎饼怎么办啊
Now, where did we land on those pancakes?
嗨  嗨
Hi. Hi.
抱歉   我没办法把门锁上
Sorry about that, but I couldn't get that lock to work on the door.
没关系  我搬进来时  乔伊就把它弄坏了
Yeah, Joey kind of disabled it when I moved in.
你一定是瑞秋  我是艾玲  嗨
You must be Rachel. I'm Erin. Hi.
我不想跟高中女生一样无聊   但他有跟你谈到我吗
I don't mean this to sound like high school, but did he say anything about me?
你要吃煎饼吗
Would you like some pancakes?
老友记   第七季  第7集  罗斯的博士论文
Friends  S07E07  The One With Ross's Book
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
（大学图书馆）
快说吧  我们为什么要来这里   好吧  猜下
Come on. Why are we here? Okay, okay, take a guess.
这里有辣妹
The hot chicks?
好吧  之前我将一些名字输入图书馆的电脑里
Okay, okay, I was typing names into the library computer earlier...
你知道的  当时只是为了好玩
...you know, for fun.
我输入我的名字   你猜我发现了什么
And I typed mine in, and guess what came up?
我的博士论文
My doctoral dissertation.
它就放在大学中最大的图书馆里
It's here! Yeah, It's right down here in the biggest library in the university.
哇  那真的很酷  对
Wow, that's actually pretty cool. yes.
这里还收藏了一本书   作者是叫做温蒂巴琴娜的女人
There's also a book here by a woman named Wendy Bagina.
那是怎么一回事
What is that?
看起来这两个家伙   真的很喜欢杜威十进分类法
Sounds like two people are really enjoying the Dewey decimal system.
我们真的很抱歉
We're so sorry.
你该不会是带我来这里做那档子事吧
You didn't bring me here to do that, did you?
她又把鸡肉退回来了
She sent the chicken back again?
她说鸡肉太干  想亲自跟你解释  她要什么样的鸡肉
She said it's too dry now and she wants to come back here and explain to you how she wants it.
我倒想会会这个鸡肉专家
Well fine! I'd like to meet this chicken expert.
叫她进来吧
Send the colonel in.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
幸运的混蛋
Lucky bastard.
珍妮丝  你好吗
Janice. How are you...
高级大餐厅里   处理上等鸡肉的辣妹大厨师
...Ms. Hotshot-Chef-at-the-Big-Fancy Restaurant-With-the-Best-Chicken-Ever?
我很好
I'm fine.
你手上戴了什么   我看不见了
Oh, what is that on your finger? I'm blind.
谁是那个幸运的男人
So who's the lucky guy?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我真的很抱歉   甜心
I am so sorry, sweetie.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你没有告诉她  我们将会结婚吧
You didn't tell her we were getting married, did you?
她看到戒指了  她被吓到了吗
She saw the ring. Did she freak out?
她的确被吓了一大跳   但很多人都吓了一大跳
She was shocked when I told her, but then again, so were most people.
肯定啊
Right
事实上她也交了男朋友
Well, She actually has a boyfriend y'know herself.
他叫做克拉克
Name's Clark.
她还邀请自己来参加我们的婚礼
She also invited herself to our wedding.
还有克拉克
Clark too.
你拒绝了她吧
You said no, right?
她逼得我头晕  还质问我  婚礼是不是在城里举行
Well, she cornered me. She asked me if the wedding was in town.
我该怎么办   说谎骗她
I mean, What was I supposed to do? Lie.
那会有多难呢  "你的支票寄出去了"
How hard is that? "Your check's in the mail."
"你的宝宝好可爱"
"Oh, your baby's so cute."
"我等不及要看你的书  罗斯"
"I can't wait to read your book, Ross."
她会来参加婚礼  或许并不是件坏事
Come on! So she comes to the wedding. Maybe it won't be so bad.
你以为她会安静地坐着   你不认为她会想举杯致词吗
What do you think she'll sit quietly? You don't think she'll want to make a toast?
你不认为她会想唱 《兼职情人》吧
You don't think she'll want to grab the microphone and sing "Part-Time Lover"?
我的天啊   她不会喜欢鸡肉  对吧
Oh, my God. She's not gonna like the chicken that night either, is she?
你知道吗  一定会没事的
You know what? It'll be okay.
或许她根本不想来
Y'know what? She's probably not gonna even want to come.
真的吗   不   那是个谎言
Really? No, that was a lie.
你知道说谎有多容易了吧
See how easy that was?
所以你会骗她吗
So you would have just lied?
我会
Yes.
它真的就那么简单   对
It would have really been that easy? Yes.
很好  那星期六表演给我看  我们要跟她和克拉克共进晚餐
Good, so do it Saturday night because we're going to dinner with her and Clark.
你们还好吗
Hey, what's up?
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
嘿   你的朋友是谁啊
Hey, who's your friend?
嘿
Hey!
嗨   乔伊   艾玲
Hey, Joey. Erin.
你还在这里
You're still here.
我们整天泡在一起   玩得很开心
Yeah, We ended up spending the day together and had such a great time.
那当然   艾玲真的很棒
Why wouldn't you? Erin is great.
你们也是
And then there's you guys.
听着  我得走了
Well, listen, I better get going.
今天真的很愉快   谢谢  我知道
Today was great. Thanks. I know.
好吧
0Kay.
乔伊   昨晚真的很棒
And Joey, last night was fun.
是啊   我再打电话给你
Yeah. I'll call you.
我也会打电话给你   我会打电话给你
I'll call you too. Or I'll call you.
打电话给我   好
And call me. Okay.
很高兴能再见到你  拜
Good to see you again. Bye.
再见  再见
Bye-bye. Bye.
那套系统已经崩溃了
So the system kind of broke down, huh?
乔伊  对不起  我没办法告诉她那些话
Oh Joey, I'm sorry. I just couldn't tell her all those things you wanted me to tell her.
我们开始聊起天来  我
And y'know we got to talking, and I--
我们要你娶她
We want you to marry her.
什么
What?
她真的很棒   你根本不了解她
She is so amazing. You have no idea.
不了解   你觉得是谁把她带回来的
No idea? Who do you think brought her here?
丘比特
Cupid.
她真的好酷   还会说四种语言
Joey, she's so cool. She speaks four languages.
天啊   你们真的知道男人想要什么
Man, do you know what guys want.
别这样   她跟你是天生的一对   她真的很漂亮
Look Joey, Come on, she's so perfect for you. I mean She's sweet.
她喜欢棒球   午餐时喝了两瓶啤酒
She likes baseball. She had two beers at lunch.
我的啤酒
My beers?!
听着   她真的是个好女孩
Look you guys, she's a very nice girl.
我们相处甚欢   但我不觉得我们会有什么结局
Okay. We had a very good time, but I just I don't see it going anywhere.
你总是那么说
Yeah, but you always say that.
或许只要你给她一次机会   事情就会变得不一样
Maybe if you gave this girl a chance, it would go somewhere.
对不起  我真的不那么认为
Look I'm sorry, you guys. I just don't think so.
随便你  好吧
Whatever. Fine.
嘿  别开始评论我
Hey, don't start judging me.
你爱上了你的助理
You're the one who's in love with your assistant.
还有你  你跟在屋顶上养鸽子的男人有一腿
Huh? And you, You're the one having the affair with the guy who keeps pigeons on the roof.
菲比
Phoebe!
那是秘密恋情
Secret affair.
（中央咖啡厅）
大家在我的书面前做那档子事
People are doing it in front of my book.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
学校图书馆收藏了我的博士论文   我跑过去看
My doctoral dissertation is in the library at school. I went to see it.
发现学生们在古生物学区 "做那档子事"
And there were students making babies right in the middle of the paleontology section.
我的天啊   你有看到精彩好戏吗
Oh, my God. Did you get to see anything good?
我问问  你们念书的时候
Let me ask you something, at your school...
校园里有没有什么地方  是学生会跑去鬼混的
...was there a like uh a place on campus where students went to fool around?
没错  真的有
Yeah, there was.
图书馆的角落里  有些书根本不会有人去借
It was—there the corner of the library where all these dusty books that nobody ever read.
没错  是那里
Yes, there was.
太棒了  因为大家都会跑到那里去  像是秘密基地一样
Great, because people kept showing up. I think it's like a thing.
等一下
Hold on a second.
你是指五楼后区的墙边吗
Fifth floor, against that back wall?
我的老天爷啊
Oh, for crying out loud!
我们该去看电影了  干嘛这么急
All right, So we should go catch our movie. Well now what's the rush?
我想看预告片
I'd like to see the previews.
我想吃糖果
The candy.
嘿  看看是谁来了
Oh, hey. Well, look who's here.
嗨   乔伊   嗨  艾玲
Hey, Joey. Hey, Erin.
嗨   瑞秋  嗨
Hey, Rachel. Hi.
我们正要去看电影
We were  just about to take off and see a movie.
喔  不  怎么了
Oh, no! What's wrong?
菲比  我们忘了  我们得去参加派对
Phoebe, we forgot that party we have to go to.
喔  不会吧
Oh, no.
什么派对
What party?
生日派对
A birthday party.
谁的生日派对
Whose birthday party?
爱莉森的生日派对
Alison's birthday party.
爱莉森几岁了
Oh. And how old is Alison?
三十二岁
Thirty-two.
等一下   你们为什么不一起出去玩呢
Wait a minute. Why don't you guys do something?
这一招还真的有用
Yeah, Look how that worked out.
对不起  我是学校里的教授
Excuse me. Hi, I'm a professor here.
你知道五楼437号书架的古生物学区吗
Do you know the paleontology section, fifth floor, stack 437?
我知道  等我五分钟
Well, yes. Just give me five minutes.
我得找人来帮我代班
I just have to find someone to cover my shift.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
我能跟负责人谈一谈吗
Can I speak to someone in charge please?!
有什么事吗
How can I help you?
你好  我想问馆方能不能增加人手
Hi, I was wondering, if it is possible to increase security...
巡逻古生物学区
...in the paleontology section?
我写的书放在那里
I wrote a book that's up there.
但大家去那里不是看书  而是
And instead of reading it, people are...
他们在我的书面前打滚
Well, they're rolling around in front of it.
我们知道你提及的问题
We are aware of the problem you're referring to.
但增加巡逻这件事   恐怕馆方的人力不足
But as far as increasing security, I'm afraid the library's very understaffed.
我帮不上你的忙
I can't help you.
好吧
Well, fine.
如果我是唯一愿意欣赏
If I'm the only person with any appreciation...
书写文字之美的人  我会亲自去捍卫它
...of the sanctity of the written word, then I'll go up there and defend it myself.
别跟着我
Don't you follow me.
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
你跟艾玲玩得还开心吗   真是不可思议
How did it go with Erin? Unbelievable.
我们玩得非常开心
We had the best time.
那你不再生我们的气了  不  你们是对的
Oh so, you're not, you're not mad at us anymore? No, no. You guys were totally right.
这次比我们第一次约会棒得多
This is so much better than the first time we went out.
第一次真的很尴尬   我们都很紧张
Y'know? That was so awkward, We were both nervous.
你们不是上过床了  对  那倒是让我冷静了下来
Didn't you sleep together? Yeah, that really calms me down.
我们有很多共通点
And we have so much in common.
她喜欢三明治  运动  虽然她是大都会队的球迷
She loves sandwiches, sports. Although she is a Met fan.
现在那都不是问题   但如果我们有了孩子
not much of an issue now, but if we had kids...
我的天啊  你竟然会提到生孩子的事
Oh, my God! Listen to you talking about having kids.
喔  我的乔伊
Oh, my Joey.
求求你别比我先结婚
Please don't get married before I do. Oh.
我不敢相信克拉克会放我鸽子
I just cannot believe that Clark stood me up.
他可能还是会来
He may still show up.
你是笨蛋吗
What are you, stupid?
我们已经等了三小时  只有三小时吗
It's been three hours. Is that all?
谈一些比较快乐的事吧
Let's go on to happier things. okay?
为什么不告诉我你们的婚礼呢
Why don't you tell me about your lovely wedding?
关于我们的婚礼  有一件事我们想告诉你
Well actually uh, there was something that we wanted to tell you about the wedding.
婚礼的规模很小
It's going to be a small ceremony.
小到不行
Uh, Tiny.
我们甚至不知道为什么要举行婚礼
We're not even sure why we're having it.
事实上我们只会邀请了家人来参加
It's actually we wants to be just family.
喔   等一下
Oh, wait.
你们把我当家人看待
You two think of me as family?
我得问你们一件事   请老实地回答我
Oh,  I have to ask you something now, and be honest.
你们要我唱《无心呢喃》 还是《红衣女郎》
Do you want me to sing "Careless Whisper" or "Lady in Red"?
你怎么能那么说   大都会队也好不到哪里去
How can you say that? The Mets have no closer.
班尼提兹呢   第一场比赛呢
What about Benitez? What about game one of the Series?
你为什么不闭嘴   你才要闭嘴
What about shut up? You shut up.
我喜欢跟她吵架
I love arguing with her.
我马上回来  好
Be right back. Okay.
你跟乔伊进行得如何
So how's it going with Joey?
还好
Oh, okay.
Okay?
请告诉我你喜欢他   告诉我你真的喜欢他
Wait okay, tell me that you like him, please. I mean, tell me that you like him.
他真的很棒  我知道  你们希望我们能成功
Look, he's a really great guy, and I know you really want this to work out...
但我不觉得我们会有未来
...but I just don't see this having a future.
但你说过你喜欢他   发生了什么事
But you said that you liked him. I mean what happened?
你改变主意了吗
Did you just change your mind?
可以那么说   那么快改回来啊
Kind of. Then change it back!
对不起  我们之间真的没有火花
I'm sorry. It's just there's no real spark.
没有火花   你们不是都上过床了吗
No spark? Didn't you sleep together?
是啊
Yeah.
荡妇
Ugh, tramp!
乔伊知道吗
Does Joey have any idea?
我想他不知道   你知道吗
I really I don't think he does. And you know what?
或许你们可以告诉他  我不想
Maybe you guys could help clue him in. Y'know, tell him I'm not interested...
认真地跟别人交往
...in a serious relationship or something.
你是说你是个独行侠
You mean, like, that you're kind of a loner?
对  那个说法不错
Yeah, that'd be great.
或许你真的是个淫娃   你说什么
And maybe that you're a real stronzo. I'm sorry?
我猜你会说的四种语言里   不包括意大利语吧
Oh well, I guess Italian isn't one of the four languages you speak.
嘿   要走了吗   对啊  我们走吧
Hey. Want to go? Yeah, let's go.
待会见   再见
Okay. See you guys later. Bye, guys.
嘿   谢谢你们
Hey, thank you so much.
我猜不是丘比特把她带来这里的
I guess it wasn't Cupid that brought her here.
不   只是一个会飞的老矮人
No, just a regular old flying dwarf.
怎么了   需要我帮忙吗
Yes, yes. How can I help you?
我们只是四处看看
Yeah, we were...we were just looking around.
原来你们是爱念书的学生
Oh, you're-you're fellow scholars.
你们到底在找什么
What exactly were you looking for?
或许你们想看
Perhaps--
查斯特史塔克博士
Perhaps Dr. Chester Stock's musings...
对剑齿虎的研究
...on the Smilodon californicus?
快滚
Get out of here!
你来找人吗
Meeting someone?
还是你想来看看
Or are you just here to brush up...
玛莉安对进化论的看法
...on Merriam's views on evolution?
事实上  我觉得玛莉安的观点  太先进了
Actually, I find Merriam's views far too progressionist.
我也觉得玛莉安的观点太先进了
I find Merriam's views far too progressionist.
对不起  你是哪位
I'm sorry. Who are you?
我是本校的教授罗斯盖勒
I'm a professor here. Ross Geller.
罗斯盖勒   为什么那个名字好熟  它是
Ross Geller? Why do I know that name? It's a...
等一下
Wait.
这本书是你写的吗
Did you write this?
对
Yes.
你就是借走我的书的人
You're the person who checked out my book?
你跟我想像中完全不一样
You know, you look nothing like I would have thought.
你好年轻
You're so young.
我四年级跳级了
Well, I skipped fourth grade.
我真的很抱歉
I am very, very sorry.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
嗨
Hi.
你们的约会还顺利吗  太棒了  我们在格林威治村散步
So how was your date? Oh, it was great! We walked all around the village.
还去了冰淇淋店  一起喝一杯奶昔
We went to this ice cream place. Split a milk shake.
我喝的比较多   但还是很棒
Seventy-thirty, but still.
我想带她到北区的民宿去过一夜
And guess what, I'm thinking of taking her upstate to one of those bed-and-breakfasts.
真的吗  她答应了吗
Really? She said she wants to go away with you?
不  那只是个惊喜  但那有点难  因为她说她的工作实在很忙
No-no-no-no-no! it's a surprise. but it's gonna be tricky thought because she said she was gonna be pretty busy at work for a while.
好吧  甜心  乔伊  我们得谈一谈  好吗
Joey, look, honey, we need to talk, okay?
今天她让我觉得
I got the feeling from her today...
她不想认真地跟别人交往
...that she's not looking for a serious relationship.
你怎么会那么想   是她告诉我的
Where are you getting this? She told me.
她说她是个独行侠
She said she's kind of a loner.
这样
Oh.
乔伊   嘿   瑞秋  没关系的
Joey-Hey, Rach, it's cool, you know.
我也是个独行侠  对吧
I'm a loner too, right?
乔伊   你知道吗   她配不上你
Hey, Joey. You know what? You are way too good for her.
我发誓下次我会告诉她们   你不想定下来
Yeah and honey I promise, next time I will just say good-bye and tell them you're not looking for a relationship.
不
No.
不   别那么做   只要
No, don't do that. Just...
下次确定她真的喜欢我   对   你说得没错
Next time, make sure she really likes me. Well, that too.
乔伊
Joey?
怎样
Yeah?
你要吃煎饼吗   终于问我了
Do you want some pancakes? Finally.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我们该选《无心呢喃》
I say we go with "Careless Whisper."
钱德
Chandler?
她看到我们了吗  看到我们了吗
Did she see us yet? Did she see us?
珍妮丝   你来干什么
Janice, what are you doing here?
我想回我家去
I thought I was gonna go back to my apartment...
但今晚我不想独处
...but then I just felt like I really couldn't be alone tonight.
我在想或许我可以待在你们家
I was just wondering if I could maybe stay here with you.
我真的觉得我该跟家人在一起
Just I really feel like I need to be with family.
我们的孩子会叫她珍妮丝阿姨  对吧
Our kids are gonna call her Aunt Janice, aren't they?
拜托   因为我真的不知道   我会做出什么事来
Please. Because otherwise, I really don't know what I might do.
你不会有点好奇吗
Aren't you just a teensy bit curious?
你们有面纸吗   有  在浴室里
You have any tissues? Yeah, in the bathroom.
我们得收留她
We'll just ...we'll just let her stay.
不  如果我们收留她  她会永远住在这里
No-no-no-no, If we let her stay, she will stay forever.
就像你的躺椅一样   你真的那么想
Kind of like your Barcalounger. Is that what you're thinking about right now?
我一直都是那么想
I never stop thinking about it.
嘿   两位
Hey, you guys?
你们想上洗手间吗   因为我要洗澡了
Do either one of you want to get in there before I take my bath?
珍妮丝   对不起
Janice, I'm sorry...
但今晚你不能留下来
...but you can't stay here tonight.
为什么
Why not?
实情吗
Honestly?
我们家因为电磁辐射的关系
Our apartment is a hotbed...
遭到了污染
...for electromagnetic activity.
摩妮卡跟我已经免疫了  但不幸地
Monica and I have been immunized, but sadly...
你没有免疫力
...you have not.
我需要一条棉被
I'm gonna to need a comforter.
你有抗过敏的棉被吗   不然的话我的鼻子会过敏
Do you have a hypoallergenic one? Because otherwise I get very nasal.
你们养猫了吗   因为我已经开始过敏了
Do you have a cat? Because it's already happening.
你们听到了吗   你们听
Eh. Do you hear that? Listen.
我的天啊   你非离开不可了
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! You have to go.
为什么
Why?
因为钱德对你还有感觉
Because Chandler still has feelings for you.
真的吗
He does?
你说什么
Say again?
没错  没错
That's right. That's right.
所以今晚你不能留下来
And that is why you can't stay here tonight.
或许你都不该来参加婚礼
And probably why you shouldn't come to the wedding.
感觉  很强烈的感觉
Feelings. Such strong feelings.
我是说我知道他对你的感觉   永远都不会完全消失
I mean, I realize that his feelings may never completely go away...
但你应该消失
...but you can.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我懂了  真的很抱歉
I understand. I am so sorry.
我会离开的
I'll go.
再见  摩妮卡
Goodbye, Monica.
我祝你跟他永远幸福快乐
I wish you a lifetime of happiness with him.
钱德
Chandler.
如果你们相处得不好   就打电话给我
You call me when this goes in the pooper.
别紧张  这片区由我来负责
Don't sweat it, I've got this section covered.
事实上我会拿着手电筒   照别人的眼睛
Yeah, in fact, I've got this baby to shine in people's eyes.
好吧  待会见
Okay, see you later.
我只是带摩妮卡来看你的书
I just wanted to show Monica your book.